Martin P. Catherwood Memorabilia /3025 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Martin P. Catherwood Memorabilia
1960-1973
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Catherwood, Martin P.
/3025 MB
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Memorabilia.
The former Dean of the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations collection of plaques, paper weights, book ends, and other memorabilia.
5931388
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 18, 2012
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, October 11, 2022
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1945 as the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, the ILR School today is advancing the world of work through teaching, research and outreach. ILR's mission is to prepare leaders, inform national and international employment and labor policy, and improve working lives, but as the world of work evolves, the school's focus broadens to keep pace with that change.
ILR studies many areas that shape the working world and contribute to an organization's success in a global economy. These include human resource management; labor-management relations; labor economics; organizational behavior; international and comparative labor; labor relations, labor law and history; conflict resolution; management development; diversity management; employment and disability; and social statistics.
An ILR education is grounded in the social sciences. Students and faculty explore and gain an understanding of human behavior through the lens of the workplace. Students also learn how organizations work and how they fit into the larger society and economy. As a result, they acquire knowledge and skills that help them to solve problems on-the-job and to build and manage productive work relationships. An ILR education, for students and professionals, is practical and applied.
ILR has more full-time faculty involved in teaching and research that spans the broad range of work and employment disciplines than any other educational institution of its kind. Its Martin P. Catherwood Library is regarded as the most comprehensive source of information in North America on work, employment and labor issues.
The Martin P. Catherwood Library, commonly known as the Catherwood Library or simply the ILR Library, serves the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University. One of over a dozen libraries within the Cornell University Library system, the Catherwood Library is considered the most comprehensive resource of its kind in North America. The Catherwood Library's stated mission is to serve as a comprehensive information center in support of the research, instruction, and service commitments of the Industrial and Labor Relations School and Cornell community. The Catherwood Library is an official Depository Library of the International Labour Organization (ILO), one of only two in the country to be so designated; the other is the Library of Congress.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3025: Martin P. Catherwood Papers /4041: Martin P. Catherwood Additional Papers /4052: Martin P. Catherwood Additional Papers /4198 MB: Martin P. Catherwood Academic Robe, Hood and Cap Additional Memorabilia /4292m: Martin P. Catherwood Letter to Joseph Raffel
Catherwood, M. P. (Martin Paul), 1904-1978; International Business Machines Corporation; International Association of Governmental Labor Officials; National Association of Realtors; Tompkins County United Way
5931388
- Desk box/paper weight from IBM Factory Organizations, Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  engraved with "Compliments of IBM Factory Organizations, Dr. M.P. Catherwood" -- silver with etchings on top of cover and inside of cover of IBM buildings
- Medal and lapel pin engraved with "Paul Harris Fellow", Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 2)
  gold coin with profile of a man, both inside a blue velvet covered box
- Bronze souvenir with Ezra Cornell and the clock tower on the front, Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 3)
  on the back engraving reads: "Presented by the Board of Trustees of Cornell University to Martin P. Catherwood With Warm Appreciation For His Great Contribution to Cornell as a Trustee, 1941-1947, 1959-1970 in a black case with red velvet lining
- Plaque - Good Government Award, 1962; Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 1)
  wooden plaque with engraving "Good Government Award Presented To Hon. Martin P. Catherwood, Industrial Commissioner, Dept. of Labor, State of New York by the New York State Careerists Society, Inc. In Acknowledgment and Appreciation of His Distinguished Contributions to the Efficient Operations of a Major Unit of Government in the Fields of Public Administration and Democratic Employee Relations. Fifth Anniversary Breakfast, October 7th, 1962
- "IAGLO to Dr. Martin P. Catherwood in Grateful Recognition of Services to the International Association of Governmental Labor Officials as President 1965-1966", Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 2)
  wooden plaque with bronze scroll and engraving -
- "Christmas 1968"; and the 'Great Seal of the State of New York' - Desk paper weight, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 3)
  gold with engraving
- Desk clock, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 4)
  round, gold desk clock made by Tiffany amp;amp;amp; Co.
- 'New York State Pavilion-New York World's Fair, 1964-1965'; side 2-'The Great Seal of the State of New York'; enclosed in a navy blue box with the etching 'to M.P.C. from N.A.R. Christmas 1964' - Bronze coin, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 5)
  engraved on both sides
- "M.P.C. from N.A.R., Christmas 1967" - Book Ends, Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 6)
  2 gold blocks one with engraving -; also includes 'The Great Seal of the State of New York'; one plain, no engraving
- Tompkins County United Way Distinguished Service Award, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  For work as the 1973 Campaign Chairman